Jeff Lauritzen

13275 N. Country Club Rd. Effingham, IL 62401 | 217-536-2214 | jefflauritzen22@gmail.com

Summary

Skilled pipeline professional with over 25 years of estimating experience and extensive knowledge of projects in the oil, liquid, industrial & natural gas piping industry, pipeline & piping station fabrication and integrity maintenance work, as well as having experience as a material and manpower coordinator, project manager & operation manager and day to day coordination with field crews.

Education

BACHELOR'S DEGREE | 1993 | INDIANA STATE UNIVERSITY

· Major: Industrial & Mechanical Technology

DIPLOMA | 1987 | MARTINSVILLE HIGH SCHOOL, ILLINOIS

· Major: High School Diploma

Experience

VP FIELD OPERATIONS | BIGINCH FABRICATORS | 2018 - PRESENT

Responsible for overseeing shop operations, including cost control tracking of operations, rework BigInch policies & procedures and oversee the safety/OQ department. Member of Local 157 Plumbers & Pipefitters union.

VICE-PRESIDENT | INFRASOURCE | 2017 - 2018

Responsible for managing construction groups overall project performance including meeting deadlines, working safely, delivering quality, overseeing cost control, completing pre-job notifications for all projects and customer deliverables. Duties, also include meeting with customers and growing customer relationships

ESTIMATOR/OPERATIONS MANAGER | FOLTZ WELDING | 2007 - 2017

Responsible for the estimating and cost for all projects, effectively project manage all projects with kickoff meetings, setting up budgets, coordinating equipment and manpower, oversight of project schedules, as well as certify that work is constructed in accordance with project plans and specifications. Maintained working relationships with all team members, customer engineers, subcontractors and weekly job reporting requirements.

PROJECT MANAGER/ESTIMATOR | TOTAL MECHANICAL | 2000 - 2007

Responsible for overseeing industrial piping projects as well as estimating for all projects, day to day communication with owners and onsite foreman. Roles included setting up budgets, ordering material, weekly forecast meetings and project schedules.